{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "In concentration polarisation flux decline occurs due to",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Reaction between membrane and permeate stream",
        "b": "Accumulation of solute molecules on the membrane surface",
        "c": "High bulk concentration",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What happens to the membrane surface concentration as time progresses?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increases",
        "b": "Decreases",
        "c": "Increases and reaches a constant value",
        "d": "Remains constant throughout"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which side of the membrane the osmotic pressure is higher?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Solution side",
        "b": "Solvent side",
        "c": "Equal both sides",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The effective pressure driving force for solvent flow from solution side to solvent side is(∆P is external pressure difference given)",
      "answers": {
        "a": "∆P-∆∏",
        "b": "∆∏",
        "c": "∆P",
        "d": "∆P+∆∏"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The pore size range for a reverse osmosis membrane is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.1-1 nm",
        "b": "10 nm",
        "c": "1000 nm",
        "d": "100 µm"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "A UF membrane has a pore-size range of",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1-100 A",
        "b": "1-100 µm",
        "c": "1-100 nm",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": " A Nanofiltration membrane has a pore-size range of",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1nm",
        "b": "10nm",
        "c": "1µm",
        "d": "100µm"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The concentration of NaCl in sea water is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "0.5 molal",
        "b": "0.5 molar",
        "c": "5 molar",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is effect of increasing pressure on flux?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increases",
        "b": "Decreases",
        "c": "Remains constant",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "When bulk concentration increases what happens to flux?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Increases",
        "b": "Decreases",
        "c": "constant",
        "d": "None of these"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "Explanation 1  <a href='www.google.com'>here</a>",
        "b": "Explanation 2",
        "c": "Explanation 2",
        "d": "Explanation 2"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
